The true story of two sisters who shared a passion, a madness, and a man.
Hilary and Jackie is a drama, music film directed by Anand Tucker.
The tragic story of world-renowned cellist Jacqueline du Pré, as told from
the point of view of her sister, flautist Hilary du Pré-Finzi.
Jackie Du Pré, played by Emily Watson.
Hilary Du Pré, played by Rachel Griffiths.
Daniel Barenboim, played by James Frain.
Kiffer Finzi, played by David Morrissey.
Derek Du Pré, played by Charles Dance.
Iris Du Pré, played by Celia Imrie.
Hilary and Jackie is a 1998 British biographical film directed by Anand Tucker, starring Emily Watson and Rachel
Griffiths as the British classical musician sisters Jacqueline du Pré (cello) and Hilary du Pré (flute).
The film covers Jacqueline's meteoric rise to fame, her alleged affair with Hilary's husband Christopher "Kiffer" Finzi, and
her struggle with multiple sclerosis starting in her late 20s ultimately leading to her death at the age of 42.
Frank Cottrell-Boyce wrote the screenplay at the same time that siblings Hilary and Piers du Pré were working on their
memoir, published in 1997 as A Genius in the Family (later republished under the title Hilary and Jackie).
As such, the film's closing credits states that it is based on the memoir, though Cottrell-Boyce confirmed, in a programme distributed
at early showings of the film, that: "Hilary was working on the book at the same time as I was working on the film ...
it was at a very early stage when we were doing the script".
The film was not intended as a documentary and thus, unlike the book, does not
claim to be the true story and includes some fictionalised incidents.
When it was released, the film attracted controversy when several personal friends of Jacqueline publicly condemned it for allegedly
distorting details in her life, while Hilary publicly defended it as her and Piers's version of the family's story.
Hilary and Jackie generally received critical acclaim, and both Griffiths and Watson were nominated
for an Academy Award, for Best Supporting Actress and Best Actress, respectively.
The film explores themes of career, london, england,
concert, sibling relationship, musician.
The tone is emotional.